# Miguel Augusto Sales do Amaral

Fullstack developer with more than 2 years of experience building scalable applications with good practices and clean code. During this brief journey, I was able to contribute and learn in several business areas, such as sales systems and project management. I am willing to face big challenges and reach higher places.

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

## **Datamétrica, Recife** — Telecommunications operator

Jun 2023 - ago 2023

- Receptive services;
- ROI/SAC/Card holder;

## **Freelancer** — Desenvolvimento de projetos SPA

MARCO DE 2022 - Atual

#### • Product Reviews and Comments System:

Description: Develop a product reviews and comments system for the e-commerce platform, enabling users to provide feedback, rate products, and engage in comment threads. Users should be able to respond to comments. Technologies:I work with React for the frontend

#### Revamped Restaurant Website Design:

Description: Implement a fresh layout and enhanced functionalities for a restaurant website using Styled Components and React. The new design should focus on improving user experience, showcasing menu items, and providing an intuitive reservation system. Styled Components will be utilized for consistent and styled UI elements throughout the website.

Technologies: I was able to work alone on this project. I use React, Styled Components and JavaScript.

# • Online Payment Integration:

Description: Integrate an online payment option into the e-commerce website, leveraging popular payment gateways like Stripe or PayPal. Ensure secure transaction processing and provide users with clear payment confirmations. Technologies: I was able to learn Java with spring boot with a coworker, it was used for backend payment processing and I was responsible for using React with Typescript for the frontend.

## **Technical support internship , Recife** — ScriptCase(RAD)

out 2023 - Atual

- Service to national and international customers via chat and email
- Check and report inconsistencies in the Scriptcase tool
- Install web environments (Apache, PHP, Scriptcase and MySQL)
- Documentation translation and creation
- Configuring multiple relational databases

#### **Skills:**

- Technologies for web/mobile development: Proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Java, C,C++,C#, Javascript, Typescript, ReactJS, React Native,NextJS, TailwindCss, StyledComponents;
- Web Services: REST, SOAP, JSON Services;
- Technologies for data manipulation: Basic knowledge of MySQL, MongoDB, Excel;
- Agile methodologies: Scrum, Kanban, XP;
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MacOS;
- Soft Skills: Clear and effective communication, problem solving, humanized customer service, self-management, ease of working in a team and dividing tasks, emotional intelligence, focus on delivering results;

Recife, Pernambuco **81 99637-9353** 

miguel.amaral.sales@gmail.c

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ miguel-augusto-8b7350217/

https://miguelsales.vercel.ap p/

#### **COURSES**

HTML5 CSS3- Gustavo
Guanabara-Curso em video;
Javascript - Matheus
Battisti - Udemy
ReactJs and NextJs - Luíz
Otávio Miranda - Udemy;
React Native - Cod3r Cursos
Online - Udemy;
TailWInd- Matheus
Battisti-Udemy;

**Git and Github- Matheus Battisti-**Udemy;

PHP- Matheus Battisti-Udemy;

NodeJS- Matheus Battisti-Udemy;

Python-Gustavo Guanabara -

Curso em vídeo;

C e C++ - One Day Code-Udemy;

C# - Nelio Alves- Udemy; Java-DIO;

Java-Nelio Alves-Udemy;

MySQL- Matheus Battisti-Udemy;

**MongoDB - Matheus Battisti -** Udemy;

**AGILE-Gustavo Farias -** Udemy;

## Languages

English- C1 Spanish - B2

## **Education**

## Faculdade Senac PE —

Análise e desenvolvimento de software Ago 2020 - current